Thomas Kiley

I am a programmer proficient in C#, C++ and Unreal Engine. I have 3 years industry experience, including working as a programmer at Born Ready Games where we shipped Strike Suit Zero. I am the sole programmer at In Mind Games where I have been responsible for prototyping a sailing game and a management game. I have a 1st class honours degree in Discrete Mathematics from the University of Warwick.

Skills

C# 1 year industry experience at doublesix and In Mind Games, final year project, personal projects

C++ 3 years industry experience at Born Ready Games and In Mind Games

UE4 2 years industry experience at In Mind Games

Unity Final year project, many personal projects and game jams

Experience

In Mind Games

July 2014 - Present

- Sole programmer responsible for developing two games in Unreal Engine 4
- Implemented various gameplay systems as we prototyped different control systems
- Implemented an ocean simulation based on Gerstner Waves that featured a translucent ocean and a physics driven buoyancy model
- Prototyping a game in C# using WinForms
- Developed automated testing for Fractured Space for Edge Case Games
- Working independently and remotely

Born Ready Games

July 2012 - July 2013 (Intercalated Year)

- Released Strike Suit Zero http://store.steampowered.com/app/209540
- Gained one year of industry experience using C++ within the context of the (in house) game engine.
- Refactored the save system to support multiple save files.
- Responsible for the two ships (Raptor & Marauder), experimenting with different gameplay mechanics and balancing the ships.
- Bug fixing across the code base, including debugging **Lua** scripts, particularly in the run up to launch.

doublesix games

September 2010 - January 2012 (Holiday Employment)

• Created some tools in **C#** for the in house engine including a level editor, a particle system editor and material designer similar to that found in Unreal Engine.

References are available upon request.

Education

University of Warwick 2010 - 2014	1st Class Honours BSc in Discrete Mathematics with Intercalated Year Discrete Mathematics is a joint degree run by the Computer Science and Mathematics departments.
	 Key Modules: Advanced Topics in Algorithms (parallel computation) Linear Algebra Compiler Design Artificial Intelligence
Guildford County School 2003-2010	A-Levels: Further Mathematics - A*; Computing - A*; Mathematics - A; Physics - B AS-Levels: History - A 9 GCSE's including A* in Maths and Science, 5 As (including French and Latin) and 2 Bs

Projects

Portfolio

You can read about the various projects I have done at http://www.tkiley.co.uk.

Third Year Project - Component based AI Tool

Julv 2013 - June 2014

- Final year project designed and developed independently.
- C# application to create AI behaviours from a network of smaller behaviours, code behaviours and functions.
- I wanted to create a tool which would allow designers the ability to construct AI behaviours without having to deal with coding and low level issues such as physics. This was inspired by the AI code in Strike Suit Zero, and designers frustration at the fact that any changes had to be written by coders.
- Creating an example game in Unity3D to demonstrate different Als that can be created in the tool.

"Pub?" - Android App for organising a trip to the pub

January 2012 - March 2012

- I was Project Manager of our five person team. We made an **Android** app in **Java** for organising trips to the pub.
- Competition run by Atos in which we came fourth out of 80 teams globally. This involved giving a presentation to a board of senior Atos employees about the app and its development.
- The app ranked the user's friends based off their Facebook activity, current locations and history to try and predict whether to invite them to the pub.

Multiple "48 Hour Game Jams"

2009 - 2016

- Involves making a game in less than 48 hours, with a team of people met at the event.
- Used a wide variety of technologies including Unity, UDK, XNA and Flash.

Other Interests

In my spare time I develop personal projects and games, particularly in **Unity**. I also frequent StackOverflow (http://stackoverflow.com/users/958004/t-kiley), enjoying finding new problems and helping people solve them. I have used a number of different IDEs, including **Visual Studio**, and several source control solutions, including **Perforce** and **Git**.

Naturally, I play a lot of games and have recently been enjoying *Cave Story* and *Keep Talking*. I set up and help run a Code Club in our local library teaching children Scratch and Python. I was the campaign manager for the Green Party in central Oxford. I also take a great deal of pleasure in studying mathematics, even (in fact, particularly) when it is completely abstract and seemingly unusable! I like to go cycling during the weekends. When I can, I love going to gigs.